- 나 왔어
- 그래
Sorry I'm late.
Did I miss anything?
늦어서 미안해
무슨 일 있었어?
조이가 오레오 15개를
한입에 넣었어
Joey stuffing fifteen Oreos
in his mouth.
Fifteen?
15개? 신기록이구나
Your personal best!
Where were you?
어디 갔다 왔어?
데이트
On a date.
뉴욕주 박물관에 가다
기차에서 만난 여자야
I met this girl on a train
going to a museum upstate.
-Which museum?
-How'd you meet her?
- 어떻게 만났는데?
- 무슨 박물관?
No. Answer his.
아니, 얘 질문이 낫다
We were at the back of the train.
내가 기차 뒤쪽
문 옆에 앉아있어서
I sat near the door
so she'd have to pass by me...
칸을 옮기려면
날 지나쳐야 했지
...if she wanted to switch cars.
She was totally at my mercy.
덫에 걸린 거야
Were you so late because
you were burying this woman?
그 여자 파묻고
오느라고 늦었냐?
I'm late because
she lives in Poughkeepsie.
그 여자 집이 포킵시였어
She seems great,
but she's two and a half hours away.
괜찮은 여자인데
두 시간 반 거리야
How can she be great
if she's from Poughkeepsie?
포킵시 여자가 괜찮아 봤자지
That joke would have killed
in Albany.
올버니에선 배꼽 잡는 조크야
Done! I did it.
끝! 해냈다
이제 누가 바보냐
Who's stupid now?
The One with the
Girl From Poughkeepsie
Look! They're lighting
the big Christmas tree tonight.
이걸 봐, 오늘밤에
성탄절 트리 점등식한대
That paper is two weeks old.
2주 전 신문이야
Who keeps leaving old newspapers
in the trash?
누가 자꾸 쓰레기통에
옛날 신문을 넣지?
캐시랑 같이 가려고 했는데
I really wanted
to take Kathy to this.
At least you have somebody
to miss stuff with.
넌 같이 갈 사람이라도 있지
이 좋은 시절에 난 혼자다
I hate being alone
this time of year.
Next it's Valentine's Day...
좀 있으면 발렌타인데이
다음엔 내 생일, 그리고 땡!
...then my birthday, then bang!
Before you know it, they're
lighting that damn tree again.
또 망할 트리에 불을 켜겠지
아무나 좀 붙어라!
I want somebody!
You know, I want a man!
남자가 필요해
It doesn't even have to be
a big relationship. Just a fling!
심각한 사이는 바라지도 않아
한때 불장난이라도 좋다구
I didn't think girls ever
just wanted a fling.
여자들은 불장난 싫어하잖아
잘 모르나 본데
불장난해본 기억이 까마득하다
Let me tell you, it's been
a long time since I've been flung.
I know what I'm giving you
for Christmas.
너 성탄절 선물 정했다
There are nice guys in my office.
Want me to set you up?
우리 사무실에 괜찮은 남자
많은데 소개시켜 줘?
그래
I've been single a long time.
Why haven't you offered before?
나 싱글 된 게 언제인데
지금 이런 얘기를 해?
I have a girlfriend.
I'm happy.
난 여자친구가 있고 행복해
I no longer go out of my way
to stop others from being happy.
이제는 남의 행복도
막을 이유가 없지
Okay.
좋아
No accountants.
회계사는 싫어
And no one from "legal."
I don't like boring jobs.
법조계 인사도 사양할래
따분한 직업은 질색이야
그럼 로스는 뭐야
사자 조련사?
And Ross was what?
A lion tamer?
What's wrong, Mon?
왜 그래?
Everybody at work still hates me.
식당 사람들이 아직 날 싫어해
Is it because of the review
you wrote or something new?
그 평론 때문이야?
아님 다른 거?
It's the review.
평론이군
I was making headway.
다들 날 보고 웃어서
혼자 뿌듯했는데
Everyone was smiling at me,
and then I get off work...
퇴근하고 보니까
이게 적혀있더라
...and find out they wrote this
on my chef's hat.
꺼져라, 망할 계집
Maybe they meant to write
"Quiet, Bitch."
'시끄러, 망할 계집'을
잘못 쓴 게 아닐까?
What's the matter?
뭐가 잘못됐어?
Fine! Just trying to be nice.
묻지도 못하겠네
I haven't been picked on this much
since kindergarten.
유치원 때 이후로
이렇게 당하긴 처음이야
And they brought in someone from
junior high to do the see-saw with me.
같이 시소 탈 짝도 없어서
중학생을 불러 왔었다니까
They're trying to make me quit.
If it were any other job, I would.
날 몰아내려고 작당들을 했어
나도 그래주고 싶지만
평생 기다려왔던 직장이야
But I've waited for this
my whole life.
상사는 너니까
야단치고 해고시켜버려
Wait, you're the boss.
Yell at them. Or fire them!
그게 마음처럼 되니?
난 그렇게 모질지 못해
I would love to, but I can't.
I'm not good at confrontation.
You know what you can do?
좋은 방법이 있어
오손 웰스라는 감독은
I read about this director,
Orson Welles...
...who, at the beginning, would
hire somebody just to fire them.
공개적으로 해고하려고
사람을 따로 고용했대
Then they would all know who was boss.
누가 보스인지 보여주는 거지
난 지금 백수니까
해고당해도 좋아
I'm not doing anything.
Why not fire me?
It's a good idea.
Can you waiter?
멋진 생각이다
웨이터 할 수 있어?
Good enough to get fired.
잘릴 정도는 되지
좋아, 널 쓸게
All right. You're hired!
- 야!
- 왜?
That's why I got fired last week!
Does Orson Welles direct commercials?
나도 그래서 잘렸나 보다
오손 웰스가 버거킹 광고 찍냐?
Yes.
그렇단다
I say, Drew?
Are you seeing anybody right now?
이봐, 드류
요즘 만나는 사람 있어?
I'm not asking for me.
나랑 사귀자는 게 아니고
I'm not gay.
I'm not asking you out.
난 게이 아냐, 오해하지 마
난 절대 게이 아냐
I'm not gay.
I didn't think you were gay.
게이라고 생각한 적 없는데
지금은 그렇게 보여
I do now.
내 친구 레이첼
한번 만나볼래?
My friend, Rachel,
wants to be set up.
실연 당한 지 얼마 안돼서
심각한 관계는 싫어
I just got out of
a big relationship.
I'm not looking to get serious.
걔도 그냥 가볍게
만나는 게 좋댔어
That's okay. A fling
might be all right with her.
Is this "Hot Rachel" that
you took to the Christmas Party?
성탄절 파티에서 봤던
'뜨거운 레이첼' 말야?
By the way, that is her full name.
그렇게 통하기도 하지
Wow! I'm free for her.
이런, 내가 지원할게
Wait, I didn't say I wasn't free.
누가 안 한다고 했어?
챈들러, 내일 레인저 게임
보면서 얘기하자
Let's talk it over
at the Ranger game.
Hold on.
I just got a box of Cubans.
잠깐, 쿠바 시가 한 상자가
생겼는데 5시쯤 갖다 줄까?
I'll bring them
by your office at five.
That's a little later
than I usually stay, but sure.
퇴근시간 후지만
좋도록 하지 뭐
Before the game, we could enjoy
some eight-year-old Basil Haydens.
게임 전에 8년 묵은
베이즐 헤이든스 한잔 어때
I don't know what that is,
but that's a pretty nice jacket.
그게 뭔지는 모르지만
그 재킷은 참 멋지다
Kind of like that tie too.
넥타이도 좋은데?
Keep your pants on, man.
바지 추스르게, 친구!
I'm writing a holiday song for everyone.
Do you want to hear it?
내가 만들고 있는
명절 노래 들어볼래?
좋아
Happy Hanukkah, Monica
행복한 하누카, 모니카
성탄절엔 눈 내리리, 조이
May your Christmas be snowy, Joey
새해엔 복 받으러
로스와 챈들러
Happy New Year, Chandler and Ross
Spin the dreidel, Rachel
돌려라 팽이, 레이첼
Pheebs, that's great!
- 정말 근사하다
- 그렇지?
But you know,
Rachel doesn't rhyme with dreidel.
근데 레이첼과 팽이는
운이 안 맞아
I know, but it's so hard.
Nothing rhymes with your stupid name!
바보 같은 네 이름과는
운이 맞는 게 없어
What are you talking about?
Lots of things rhyme with Rachel:
무슨 소리야, 레이첼과
운 맞는 게 얼마나 많은데
Bagel, mail, jail, bail, cable.
베이글, 메일, 제일
베일, 케이블... 메이폴
Maypole.
All good. Thanks.
다 좋다, 고마워
Do you, maybe, have a nickname
that's easier to rhyme?
운 맞추기 쉬운 별명은 없니?
Didn't your dad used to call you
"Pumpkin"?
너희 아빠가 호박이라고 했잖아
그래
Pumpkin? But did he ever
call you "Budolph"?
호박? '부돌프'는 아니었어?
Hello, children.
- 안녕, 얘들아?
- 어서 와
Have I got the 50 guys for you!
무려 50명이나 지원했다
-Really?
-I showed them your picture.
정말?
네 사진을 보여줬더니
정신을 못 차리더라
Guys are throwing themselves at me
and giving me stuff.
술을 산다, 선물을 준다
오늘 닉스 게임 어때
-Knicks tonight?
-Where are the seats?
자리가 있어?
골라잡아
표가 20장이야
Wherever! I've got 20.
Will I like any of these guys?
나한테 맞는 남자 있어?
You know, I'm going to...
아무래도 밑밥을
좀더 던져봐야겠어
...play the field a little bit more.
챈들러
퇴직연금까지
내 앞으로 돌려준대
Guys are signing over
their 401 Ks to me.
너 로봇이랑 일하니?
You work with robots?
Yes.
네
One guy, Patrick, you'll like him.
He's nice, funny and a swimmer.
패트릭이란 친구가 있는데
준수하고 재미있고 수영도 잘해
I like swimmers' bodies.
몸매 좋겠다
아버지는 신용카드의
자기테이프를 만드셨지
His dad made the magnetic strip
on credit cards.
신용카드도 좋은데
I like credit cards!
중매쟁이 나서도 되겠다
I'm not bad at this!
-What does he do?
-He works in fine foods.
무슨 일을 하는데?
정밀식품부 소속이야
너희 회사에 그런 부서도 있어?
-You have a fine foods division?
-It's a big company....
워낙 회사가 크다 보니까...
잠깐, 로봇도 만들고
식품도 만드냐?
Now, wait a second.
You make food and robots?
No, the robots just work for them.
아냐, 로봇은 일을 하지
All right, I'm going to work.
일하러 가야겠다
Does anybody have
a problem with that?
누가 불만 있나?
그렇소, 아가씨
내가 불만 있수다
Yeah, lady. I do!
I got a problem!
진짜 불만스럽게 해줄까?
I'll give you a problem!
어떡할 건데
날 자를 거요?
What will you do?
Fire me?
You bet your ass I'll fire you!
확실하게 잘라주지
-See you later.
-Thanks.
- 이따 봐
- 고마워
그만 가볼게
데이트가 있어
I should go.
I've got a date.
그래? 누구랑?
With who?
포킵시에 사는 여자
기억나지?
You know the girl
who lives in Poughkeepsie?
- 그럼
- 그 여자 말고
Not her.
This is someone else.
다른 여자를 만났는데
둘 중 누구를 택해야 할지
I can't decide between the two.
The one from Poughkeepsie, though
two hours away, is pretty...
포킵시는 두 시간 거리지만
정말 예쁘고 똑똑하고 재미있어
...really smart and a lot of fun.
But this other girl,
she lives right uptown.
다른 여자는 바로 윗동네거든
미모도 별로 안 떨어지고
그 정도면 머리도 좋지만
She's just as pretty.
I guess she's smart.
She's not fun.
재미가 없어
If she's no fun,
why date her at all?
재미도 없는데 왜 만나
가까운 데 사니까
기회를 줘볼래
I want to give her a chance.
She lives so close.
And, at the end of the date,
she said something that...
저번에 헤어질 때 진짜
웃기는 농담을 했는데
...if she was kidding,
was very funny.
If she wasn't kidding, she's not fun.
She's stupid and racist.
만약 농담이 아니었다면
아둔한 인종차별주의자겠지
- 이봐
- 어서 와
How was your first day
at the restaurant?
식당 일은 어땠어?
Damn!
아뿔싸!
- 여기
- 그래
What happened to your fancy jacket?
옷이 왜 그 모양이야
They baked it.
저 인간들이 구웠대
더는 못 참겠어
오늘밤에 널 자를 거야
I can't take this anymore.
-I'm going to fire you tonight.
-You got it.
알았어, 이런!
What are you doing?
왜 이래
아직 불씨가 남았어
You're still on fire there.
저런, 고마워
I think you got it!
다 꺼졌어!
Chandler, you have
the best taste in men.
챈들러, 너 남자 취향이
가히 예술이다
Like father, like son.
부전자전이겠지
Patrick and I had such
a great time last night!
패트릭하고 너무 즐거웠어
꽤 심각해질 거 같아
This could, maybe, get serious.
I thought you weren't looking
for serious. Just a fling?
심각한 관계는 싫고
그냥 즐기고 싶다면서
Well, you know, possibly.
그걸 생각이었지만...
You didn't tell him that,
though, right?
그렇게 얘기한 건 아니지?
아니?
You told this guy that
I was looking for a fling?
즐길 상대를 찾는다고 했어?
그런 말을 하면 어떡해!
-You don't tell him that!
-Why not?
왜? 나라면 새끈한 여자가...
오! 이제 알겠다
I'd be thrilled if some hot girl
I see.
You telling him I want a fling
and me putting out...
그런 얘길 듣고 내 행동을
보면서 무슨 생각을 했겠어
...he's so going to get
the wrong idea!
Joey, could you pass the cheese?
조이, 치즈 좀 줘요
네
조이라고 부르지 마
I'd prefer you didn't call me Joey.
날 아는 사람이 없으니까
멋진 별명을 쓰고 싶어
I thought it might be fun
to try out a cool nickname.
Hey, Dragon!
이봐, 드래곤
Here's your tips
from Monday and Tuesday.
월요일과 화요일 팁에서
자네 몫이야
There's $300 in this one.
여기에만 300달러네?
그래, 명절 땐 팁이 후해
꽉 끼는 바지를 입어봐
People get generous
around the holidays.
And it never hurts
to wear tight trousers.
좋아요
Could the waiters listen
to the specials?
오늘의 요리 말인데요
먼저 망고 향을 가미한
칠레산 농어하고...
There's Chilean sea bass
with a mango relish
Why is nobody writing these?
왜 안 받아 적죠?
We can remember them.
외우면 되니까요
Because you'll make up fake specials
and make me cook them?
어제처럼 가짜 오늘의 요리로
날 골탕 먹일 생각인가요?
Sure, that too.
네, 그것도 있죠
좋아요, 요리는 접어두고
내 얘기 잘 들어요
Forget the specials for a minute.
Here's the thing....
For the last two weeks I have...
지난 2주 동안 난...
좋은 분위기를 만들어보려고...
...tried hard to create
a positive atmosphere.
안 들리네요!
Can't hear you!
Positive atmosphere.
만들어보려고 했는데 나도
지금 여기까지 올라왔어요
But I've had it up to here.
From now on,
it is going to be my way...
이제부터 내 방식대로
밀고 나가겠어요, 됐죠?
...or the highway. All right?
Does anybody have
a problem with that?
불만 있는 사람 있나요?
Hey, new guy.
이봐, 신참
I said, does anybody
have a problem with that?
방금 불만 있냐고 물었어요
No, ma'am.
없습니다
이 친구도 이름이 있어요
드래곤이라고
He has a name. It's Dragon.
당신 이름은 모자에 있을 거요
You want to know your name?
Check your hat.
We did the hat, right?
모자 손봤지?
-What the hell just happened?
-I am so sorry.
왜 이래?
정말 미안해
나도 협조하고 싶었어
I was going to do it.
But I was standing there
with $327 in one hand...
그런데 한 손에 327달러
다른 손에 238달러를 쥐어봐
...and $238 in the other.
And I was thinking...
이게 얼마 만에 생긴
거금이야, 무려...
...it's been a long time since I had...
...$327 plus $238!
327 더하기 238달러라고!
We had a deal! It's why you're here.
I've got to fire you!
약속했잖아, 넌 해고되려고
여기 들어온 거야
And I got to pay rent!
나도 집세를 내야 돼
그럼 이건 어때
잘리는 대신
How about you don't fire me.
Instead, I stay.
I gain their trust.
여기서 신임을 얻어
네 칭찬을 계속하는 거야
They'll listen to the nice things
I say about you.
What nice things?
어떤 칭찬?
아직은 곤란하지
까딱하면 나도 왕따 돼
Nothing yet. They hate you,
and I want to fit in.
Happy Hannukah, Chandler and Monica
Merry, merry
행복한 하누카
챈들러와 모니카...
You know what, Pheebs?
- 이거 아니?
- 뭘?
I'm not Jewish so....
난 유태인 아니거든
Ross doesn't decorate his tree
with floss...
로스는 치실로 트리장식 안 해
그래도 불평 없잖아, 시끄러!
...but he's not complaining.
Bad dream?
악몽을 꿨나?
I wasn't sleeping.
잔 거 아냐
What was Phoebe's song about?
그럼 피비가 무슨 노래했냐
고양이 노래잖아
It's the one with the cat.
I got to go.
I've got another date.
가볼게, 데이트가 있어
Did you pick one yet?
아직 결정 못했니?
It turns out the one
from uptown was making a joke.
아니, 윗동네 여자가
농담한 거라는데
It was a different joke.
It wasn't that funny.
내가 생각했던 농담이 아니었어
So I'm still torn.
아직 고민 중이야
윗동네 아가씨도 싫고
포킵시에 가기도 피곤하면
You don't like the one from uptown.
And you're exhausted
from dating Poughkeepsie.
Just end them both!
둘 다 끝내버려
포킵시에 가서
그 여자 정리하고
Go to Poughkeepsie
and break up with her.
Then break up with uptown.
오는 길에 남은 여자 정리하면
평화로운 마음으로 귀가하잖아!
By the time you get home,
you're done!
You're right. Thank you.
맞는 말이야, 고마워
나도 프라하에 살 때
그런 문제가 있었지
I had a similar problem
when I lived in Prague.
-Prague?
-So much you don't know.
프라하?
넌 모를 거야
챈들러
Patrick just ended things with me.
패트릭이랑 끝났어, 내가
진지한 관계를 원한다고 했니?
Did you or didn't you tell him
I wanted a serious relationship?
I did! I absolutely did!
물론 말했지!
You idiot!
이 밥통아!
I'm sure you're right.
But why?
맞아, 근데 왜?
You don't tell a guy that
you want a serious relationship.
남자한테 진지한 관계를
원한다고 하면 달아나버려
Now you scared him away!
I am sorry.
I am so sorry.
- 정말 미안하게 됐다
- 그 입 다시는 열지 마
You should never be allowed
to talk to people!
I know, I know!
알아, 안다구
Now I'm right back where I started.
다시 원점으로 돌아왔잖아
망할! 또 혼자야, 제길!
This sucks!
Being alone sucks!
또 나타날 거야
넌 좋은 여자니까
You'll meet somebody.
You're a great catch!
When I told those guys about you,
I didn't have to lie once.
너 다리 놓아주면서도
거짓말 하나 안 보탰어
- 진짜?
- 그럼
Really?
You graduated magna cum laude, right?
대학 차석졸업 맞지?
아니
It doesn't matter.
그게 무슨 상관이야
I got tickets to the Ranger game.
You want to come with me?
레인저 게임 티켓이
두 장 있는데 함께 갈래?
Cute guys in little shorts?
짧은 바지의 미남들? 좋아
Sure.
Actually, it's a hockey team.
Angry Canadians with no teeth.
하키 팀이야, 이빨 빠진
캐나다 싸움꾼들이지
That sounds fun too.
Thank you.
그것도 신나겠다
고마워
뭘
Okay.
Have you ever been with a woman?
여자랑 사귀어봤니?
What? What is the matter with you?
뭐? 너 진짜 못 말리겠다
언제 해도 욕먹는 질문이라니까!
There is no good time
to ask that question.
다음 역은 포킵시입니다
The station is Poughkeepsie.
Poughkeepsie!
로스? 로스
Ross? Ross?
Wake up!
일어나요, 로스?
로스, 로스! 로스!
황새치 더 필요해요
황새치 좀 줄래요?
I need more swordfish.
-Can you get me more swordfish?
-I don't speak English.
영어 못해요
방금 한 건 뭐죠?
-You just did.
-I don't know what to tell you.
할말이 없네요
Fine.
좋아요
Okay. Very funny.
네, 재미있어요
Let me out, please.
열어줘요!
춥다구요!
Come on, I'm cold!
And covered in marinara sauce!
마리나라 소스까지!
Let me out!
어서 열어요!
문고리를 찾으셨네
You found that handle, did you?
-It's not funny.
-Well, that's not true.
재미없어요
이쪽은 아닌데?
I'm a good person.
And I'm a good chef.
난 착한 사람이고
유능한 주방장인데
왜 소스를 뒤집어써야 하죠?
And I don't deserve to have
marinara sauce all over me!
If you want me
to quit this bad then
- 날 그렇게 쫓아내고 싶다면...
- 보쇼, 겔러 주방장
Chef Geller?
You know that speech you made?
어제 그 연설 말인데
난 불만 있수다
I got a problem with it!
-You do?
-You bet I do!
- 그래요?
- 물론이오
그땐 잠시 한눈을 파느라고
I just wasn't listening then,
that's all.
If you want a problem,
I'll give you a problem!
그럼 진짜 불만스럽게 해줄까?
What are you going to do?
Fire me?
어떡할 건데
날 자르시게?
확실하게 잘라주지
내 주방에서 나가!
You bet I'll fire you!
Get out of my kitchen!
Get out!
당장!
All right.
좋아, 다른 사람은
불만들 없나?
Anybody else got a problem?
How about you, chuckles?
낄낄이 아저씨는 어때
You think this is funny now?
지금도 이게 웃기나?
아뇨
What if I dance covered in sauce?
You think it's funny?
소스 뒤집어쓰고
춤추니까 웃겨 죽겠지?
No, it's really good.
아뇨, 멋집니다
Take those salads to table four.
좋아요
저 샐러드는 4번 테이블로
당신은 황새치 내와요
And you, get the swordfish!
And you!
그리고 당신!
Get a haircut!
이발이나 해요
Last stop, Montreal.
The stop is Montreal!
종착역인 몬트리올입니다
What?
뭐?
I bet myself
that you had beautiful eyes.
예쁜 눈일 거라고 생각했는데
이거 봐요, 내 짐작이 맞았죠?
Now that I see them, I win!
네?
We're at my stop.
Would you like to have coffee?
난 여기서 내리는데
커피 한 잔 할래요?
Are we really in Montreal?
여기가 진짜 몬트리올?
Yes, we are.
맞아요
So coffee?
커피 어때요
Coffee sounds great.
커피 좋죠
Wait.
그런데 몬트리올에 사세요?
So you live in Montreal?
No, but it's only a two-hour
ferry ride to Nova Scotia.
아뇨, 노바스코샤에 사는데
배로 두 시간만 가면 돼요
주방장한테 대들기 전에
처자식 생각부터 할 걸
I should have thought
about my wife and kids...
...before I talked back
to Chef Geller.
고마워
올해 크리스마스엔
쫄쫄 굶게 생겼네
It will be a lean Christmas
at the Dragon house this year.
Enough!
- 그만!
- 알았어
쫄쫄 굶게 생겼어!
Lean, lean, lean!
친구들을 위해 특별히
만든 명절 노래랍니다
So this is a very special holiday song...
...that I wrote for some very
important people to me.
Went to the store
Sat on Santa's lap
가게 산타한테 친구들을 위해
온갖 잡동사니를 달라고 했네
Asked him to bring my friends
All kinds of crap
Said all you need is
To write them a song
하지만 노래가 더 좋다는 말씀
모르는 노래 따라하지 맙시다
Now you haven't heard it yet
So don't try to sing along
따라하지 말라고
No, don't sing along
모니카, 모니카
행복한 하누카
Monica, Monica
Have a happy Hannukah
인사하는 산타클로스
안녕, 로스
Saw Santa Claus
He said hello to Ross
And please tell Joey
잘 들어라, 조이
성탄절엔 눈 내리리!
Christmas will be snowy
레이첼과 챈들러
하으... 덩글러핸들러!
And Rachel and Chandler
즐거운 명절 맞으세요
Happy holidays, everybody!